Hello, I'm your host David Barnard. My
guest today is Josh Peleg, head of M&A
and business development at BlueThrone,
a VC-backed portfolio of consumer apps
that acquires and partners with the best
consumer apps in the business.
On the podcast, I talked with Josh about
red flags that tank app valuations, why
subscription-only apps are leaving money
on the table,
and how bootstrap founders are cashing
out for millions in months, not years.
Hey Josh, thanks so much for joining me
on the podcast today.
>> David, great to be here.
>> Uh so, you and I were hanging out in
Austin Friday
and had such a great conversation. I
think I said multiple times we should
have just like set up cameras and mics
and uh recorded that conversation.
Uh you were like, "Hey, I'm still in
Texas for a few more days." And so, here
we are in a podcast studio in Austin
recording a podcast.
>> Yeah, it's super exciting.
>> So, the first thing I wanted to talk
about is BlueThrone, the company you
work for. So, you do business
development and M&A at BlueThrone. Uh
so, what is BlueThrone?
>> Yeah, so I came from mobile gaming where
I did M&A and then jumped into
BlueThrone about a year ago. And their
strategy is really interesting. So,
essentially BlueThrone's goal is to
become the number one app acquirer in
the world.
And the way it started is pretty
different to the way it looks today. So,
the way it started was a kind of spray
and pray approach. BlueThrone saw all
these little apps doing kind of decent
revenue, and we're talking about QR code
scanners, flashlight apps, the small
radio apps that we kind of all all know
and saw back in the day. And the play
was to go wide. So, initially BlueThrone
raised a bunch of VC money, and they
bought almost 100 apps, the smaller
ones. And it was a very much go wide
approach.
And what we learned at that point was
that so many of them have been pumped
full of revenue at the time of sale,
right? So, after you buy them, they
start to die.
>> Yeah.
>> But also because they're quite shallow
products, their longevity is very
limited.
>> Yeah.
>> And we learned the lesson the hard way.
So, following this, we had like a new
shift in strategy. We went from Blue
Throne 1.0 to Blue Throne 2.0.
>> So, before we get into 2.0, uh I did
want to dig into that that first phase.
Cuz there are still a lot of buyers in
the market, and not that they're not
that they're going to, you know, ignore
the signs of a pump and dump. Not that
they're, you know, only going to buy
crappy apps or whatever. There's a lot
of players in the market who are using
Blue Throne's previous strategy of
buying a lot of apps, they're doing
decent revenue, and building that kind
of portfolio, which now Blue Throne is
not interested in, but there's a lot of
players in the market who do. So,
before we get into the new strategy,
what kind of apps were you looking for
during that time? And like, what were
the signals of a of a decent
acquisition? What signals like, you
know,
said, "Hey, don't buy this app." Cuz you
know, a lot of people listening to this
podcast, maybe they spun up a side
project, and hey, it's doing, you know,
20K in MRR, and maybe they want to flip
it. Like, what does that look like?
>> Yeah, so I would never push someone away
from flipping it at the early stage.
It's definitely doable, and
the app market today in terms of buyers
and sellers is in a is in a very liquid
position. There are lots of sellers, and
there are lots of buyers. So, if you do
want to sell, you'll probably find the
right price point.
Now, when we were doing this strategy, a
lot of things we were looking for were
financial-based. So, we were looking for
like strong EBITDA and strong revenue,
and we were less concerned with the core
app metrics, things like the retention,
the churn, conversion to paying, etc.
>> Okay.
>> looking at me, and you're smiling cuz
you're like, that sounds kind of stupid.
And we realized this the hard way,
because we saw the apps as purely
financial assets back then.
>> Gotcha.
>> Because we were looking at shallow
products, like, for example, a
flashlight app.
>> Right.
>> This is what led us to it to the next
step. But essentially, back in the day
we were viewing them more as financial
products, and I think a lot of buyers at
that
price point think of apps as financial
assets that deliver returns over X
period of time.
>> Yeah. So, in that case, you're probably
looking more for organic acquisition.
And when you say EBITDA, earnings before
interest, tax, depreciation, and
amortization. I always forget all the
all the parts of the long acronym. So,
essentially, if if you're spending 40k a
month on user acquisition and you're
making 40k a month, you have zero
EBITDA. You're not a good financial
asset. So, what you all were looking at
was apps that were great at ASO. They
had some kind of organic growth
mechanism that were just spinning off
cash. So, if that's So, if you've built
a side project app and you're making 20k
a month in MRR and you don't have a
bunch of expenses, that is attractive as
a financial asset.
>> Literally, yeah. It's exactly what you
what you did describe there. We should
also kind of identify that the time
period we're talking about, which is
kind of 3 to 4 years ago, this whole
trend of doing crazy organic on TikTok
didn't exist. So, when we say TikTok,
we're really talking about ASO,
keywords. And if you picture it, it's
really those apps that were the titles.
So, the apps that were called flashlight
app or the apps that were called QR code
scanner. It's really trying to maximize
that ASO.
>> Right. And these days, a lot of people
talk about organic TikTok as if it's
free, but they're actually paying a ton
of creators. So, similarly, if you're
making 20k a month in MRR and you are
spending 20k a month on on organic
TikTok or that's your full-time job,
it's like you're just churning out
assets. If you're going to sell that to
somebody with this more kind of
financial asset approach, the buyer is
going to say, "Oh, well, wait. You know,
40 hours a week of a great marketer's
time, you know, creating these assets
that go viral on TikTok or, you know,
whatever kind of organic motion that you
have, if it's a high either cost because
you're paying creators or a high time
cost,
you know, acquirers are generally going
to look at that as a cost basis and not
look at that kind of an app as a
financial asset, right?
>> Correct. I think us in the industry
labeling this TikTok strategy organic is
very misleading.
And even though you could pay $5 for a
single UGC video that shows off your app
with a nice CTA at the end, and you may
as well get a million, two million
views, which may convert into a a 10%
conversion rate, and you kind of get
some downloads from that. That being
said,
the time invested to get to that point
is significant, and I'm talking from
experience. We recently built this UGC
machine at BlueThrone.
It took us like 6 months to get like our
first viral video, and that's not one
person's time. That's like multiple
people across multiple disciplines doing
the research, doing the execution. So,
there is a cost associated to this
organic. But, like all great mechanisms
within the app business, you get better
over time, and you optimize, and you're
able to hit those targets faster with
less resources as you get better, for
sure.
>> So, then what would your advice be to
somebody in that position? Either
they're just getting started, and
they're thinking, "Hey, I'd love to, you
know, build this app and exit it in 12
month." I mean, I see this on Twitter
all the time. Like, "I'm going to I'm
going to build this app, and I'm going
to sell it for 100k in a year." What
would your advice be to a founder like
that today to kind of optimize that for
a meaningful acquisition?
>> So, if you're trying to optimize for a
meaningful acquisition, let's say within
a 12-month time frame, it's completely
doable, and we see it the whole time. I
think what you have to be is an
absolutely killer marketer.
>> Right.
>> It's not about your dev skills, and we
talked about this over lunch on Friday,
right?
In a time when anyone can build, and the
barriers to build are so low because of
AI helping us here,
the real differentiators are
distribution. And that's why we're
seeing, you know, the people like the
App Mafia guys, and also a ton of other
kind of people who don't make the
spotlight as much, but really amazing
marketers and distributors
scaling their apps very, very quickly
through TikTok, whether it's founder-led
content, so it's them telling their
story, whether it's them interacting
really healthily with influencers in
their niche. Uh let's take an example.
Let's say you've got a kind of Christian
religion-based app, and you connect with
the Christian religious influencers in
that niche, and you build relationships
with them, and they spin out content for
you, that can just shoot you up the
charts very quickly as well.
And it's actually these guys that we're
seeing get those exits within 12 to 18
months.
And from the buyer's perspective, like I
think if I think about Blue Thorne's
perspective here, we'll always have
concerns that an app that's only been
around for 12 to 18 months has less
historical data to put a value on top of
it, right? Cuz when you're valuing a
business, you're looking at past
performance.
That being said, that there are ways to
do it because of the beauty of apps,
which is you can measure retention and
you can measure churn and you can
measure repeated customers and you can
measure conversion of free to paying
users. So, you can pretty accurately
predict how the app's going to do as
long as you have maybe 6 to 9 months of
data from that app.
>> What would be the red flags then
that you would advise folks to try and
optimize away from? And if you're
thinking, okay, I see this app, you
know, they they sprung up from nothing,
they're doing 50k in MRR, but what are
the when you're doing due diligence,
what are the red flags you're looking
for that say, oh, this is this is either
one, a much lower multiple that we're
willing to pay, or two, just like not an
acquisition anybody would want to do?
>> That's a really good question. Let's
think about um
acquisition multiples on like a
spectrum. For those who aren't aware, a
multiple is a number you'll apply to
your annual revenue, which will give you
the valuation. And you can apply it to
your revenue or your EBITDA. But go look
that up on YouTube and you'll learn a
lot more. Essentially, multiples we can
kind of view it on a on a spectrum and
at the lower end of the spectrum, you've
got apps that are primarily doing
revenue through advertising within the
app, right? It's not very predictable.
As a buyer, I cannot uh predict that
into the future. It also depends on your
daily or monthly so, it's a little bit
hard to put a true value on. It also
depends the demographic of your users
because your ads are more valuable to
tier one base users like in the US
compared to tier three in India, for
example.
>> Right.
>> As you move towards the middle of the
spectrum, you've got ads that are
monetizing through ads and IAPs, which
is in-app purchases or one-time
purchases.
Now,
in-app purchases are great and I'm sure
we'll get on to this uh in a minute, but
they're a little bit dangerous when it
comes to valuing your app because it's
not recurring revenue. It doesn't hit
that ARR definition. Now, on the far
right of the spectrum, to get the
biggest valuation possible, you're
looking at apps that are pretty much
100% recurring revenue, so
subscription-based apps. And why is
that? It's because
as a buyer, your revenue is predictable.
If I have 12 months of data of your app,
I know how many users are going to
resubscribe when their yearly or monthly
subscription is over, so I can predict
the amount of money that your app is
going to pull in into the future, which
makes it really easy, whether it's me or
anyone else really, to basically value
the app and how much money it's going to
generate.
>> And then you do that against the
expenses.
Generally. So, you're not And And I
think that's a uh something a lot of
people get mixed up about when they're
thinking, "Oh, my app's worth hundreds
of thousands of dollars." And then, you
know, to your point earlier, if you're
an AI app and you're spending like 50%
of gross revenue on your AI costs, then
then you're going to get valued on the
remaining 50%, but if you're spending
50% on AI costs and you're spending 25%
on marketing, and you're spending 20% on
like salaries that would need to
continue in the business as an
attractive um acquisition, it's it's
looking less and less attractive as
those costs go up higher and higher. And
then the other thing I'll say, and I was
just tweeting about this yesterday, is
that what most people in our industry
call MRR and ARR are not actually MRR
and ARR. Uh so, I'll I'll get on my
soapbox for 1 sec and say monthly
recurring revenue,
annual recurring revenue, you know, in
RevenueCat, we have this great chart
now, and then I've been lobbying to to
create some additional charts around
this is that
you know once somebody's turned off that
auto renew very early in the in the
cycle and we have some data at
RevenueCat that actually shows the
highest month of people turning off auto
renew in an annual subscription is
actually the first month. And so you can
get pretty predictive of what revenue's
actually going to recur if you know that
first month of people turning it off and
then fit the curve.
And so you know when you look at your
dashboard and it says you know 100k in
MRR or you know a million dollars in
ARR, it's not ARR,
it's AR and then to get to ARR, you
really need to discount by like the
known churn stats. And whether that's
you know predicting into the future with
that first month or whether that's you
have a year or two of data where you can
look back and see what those cohorts are
retaining like. You need to discount
that by the known churn or even the
estimated churn to get a true ARR and a
true MRR cuz again, I just think it's in
consumer where the you know median
retention of an annual plan is like 35%.
It's not ARR,
it's just not.
>> That brings me on to like a really
interesting point if if we draw this
back to the kind of valuation topic
which is so often you get a founder
comment and say hey I've got x amount of
subscribers on the yearly subscription.
And it's recurring cuz it's yearly. But
the killer question is like how many
people are going to come back and pay at
the end of that time period? And if your
app has not been around for 12 months,
you cannot tell me your resubscriber
rate. You you just can't.
>> But but you can estimate it. Yeah.
>> You can estimate it. Uh but you can't
tell me for a fact how many users are
actually going to come back and and pay
that money again.
>> Yeah, totally. So high churn rate would
be one of those red flags and
>> Yeah, high churn rate would be one of
those red flags. Let's do four more and
let's just kind of list them off so
listeners have like a a
checklist, right? So top one is churn
rate because that's where your
subscription revenue is coming in it.
The churn rate kind of dictates how
stable that revenue is.
It's also a great indicator of like how
effective your product solves the
problem it set out to solve, which is
awesome. Then obviously your whole CAC
to LTV ratios are like super, super
important. Is the way you're buying
traffic profitable? Um does it have
viral potential? Um or is it capped? So,
basically knowing where the tip of your
ARR curve is going to be and how far
you've been able to push that in terms
of budget. That's number two. Number
three is basically talent, team
composition, who's in the team. You, you
know, I'm seeing so many incredible solo
founders who want to build stuff and
basically hit that kind of
million-dollar exit within a within a
year. Super doable. We've seen it happen
time and time again. A lot of deals that
we've been a part of.
However, there can be some confusion
when people say, "Hey, I'm a solo
founder." Amazing, but how many
consultants are you using? How many
outsourcers are you using? Completely
fine to use them. Everyone does and it's
a really cost-effective way of scaling
up your business.
But just great to be honest about it.
Hey, I've got X number of devs in, I
don't know, Brazil, Turkey, or India,
and I've got a marketing guy in
California. Just so you know that even
though you are a solo founder and it's
just your equity, there are other
players involved and and the buyer will
need to account for that. That's number
three. Number four is all this research
around the kind of category you're
playing in. It's a very different app
whether it's playing in education,
fitness, photo and editing, or if it is
indeed like a QR code scanner. The
competition matters. How well-funded is
the competition? How aggressive is the
competition on UA, for example? Um so,
that's so super, super important. And
the fifth point I will say has to be
whether you've raised money or not. If
you've raised money from VCs, then your
valuation is going to be inflated
because you have to keep your VCs happy.
If you haven't raised money from VCs,
then maybe you're bootstrapped or you've
done a a friends and family round, the
power is all yours. You can sell at a
lower valuation, but you're keeping a
lot more money to take home and start
your next project with or retire your
parents or buy a house or whatever it
might be. Um but I want to throw this to
you, David, because it's something we
talk about a lot at Blue Throne, which
is do you think it makes sense for
consumer apps to raise VC money in this
day and age?
>> I think it can.
And I was actually thinking about that
on the drive here of
what kinds of apps are truly investable
in 2025? And you know, looking back at
my six years of RevenueCat, you know,
I've talked to hundreds hundreds of
founders and app practitioners and you
know, all sorts of folks in my office
hours, at conferences, at you know,
random meetings I end up getting booked.
And I'll say I feel like I was a little
naive you six, five, four years ago
around
you know, just how far different apps
can be taken.
And I think in 2025, we've kind of seen
things play out enough to know
the different scale opportunities and
the true like total addressable market
of these apps. And so, I think, you
know, if you're playing in a niche where
there is not a very you know, and being
realistic about it, you know, is it a
niche where there's a high willingness
to pay? Is it uh a niche that's growing
or or going down? Like uh pickleball is
a great example. Like I talked to a
friend recently who was thinking about
building an app in the pickleball space.
It's like, "Oh, so hot right now, you
know, getting in with pickleball
influencers." And like that's all really
hot. Well, pickleball seems to have
already been like kind of like rounding
the curve
>> He's better off chasing paddle instead.
It's the new one.
>> You know, so maybe even two years ago,
it seemed like, "Oh, wow, like maybe a
pickleball app would be investable
because it's growing, your TAM is
expanding, and that kind of stuff." But
I'd say, you know, today we've seen that
curve rounded, and I think you're
looking for those kind of trends as well
of like realistically how big is this
market going to be, you know, what are
your realistic LTVs in that market? And
I think that the barrier for consumer
apps to be investable in 2025 is just
much higher. And I think we've seen some
slowdown, especially in early investing
in these kind of apps because of that.
And so, if you think you can build a
category winner in a category that has
meaningful LTV, meaningful growth,
meaningful market, you know, so fitness
apps, even I mean, even mental health is
tough these days cuz like, you know, we
saw Calm and Headspace kind of tap out,
and now they're going be more B2B, and
like, even these big kind of category
winners that, you know, 3 years ago
seemed like they were just going to keep
growing, we've seen them kind of start
the growth start to slow and see them
kind of reach saturation in some of
those markets. Um so, yeah, it's it's
tough these days. I don't I don't know
that, you know, on the spot I could come
up with any kind of formula of what I
think is investable or not, but like
taking some of
those
factors I just shared, and you know,
thinking carefully about the potential
for retention, and I mean, there's just
so much that would go into me today
saying, "Oh, yeah, slam dunk, this is
investable."
>> Mhm.
It's a good question. I've been thinking
about this a lot as well recently
because,
you know, we have so many founders come
through our doors who have raised VC
money and then regretted it, and some
who haven't raised but then want to. And
I feel very strongly that I think at
pre-seed and seed, unless you're
building something with uniquely
defensible tech, forget about it. You
just don't need it. Why? Because unlike
most businesses that need VC money, they
need the VC money to get going, to
build, to create the product. But in
consumer apps, the barrier to build is
so low, you only need maybe 10, 15,000
dollars to really get going, and that's,
you know, if you're if also if you're
paying someone to build it, right? So,
when do you need the extra money, like
the cash injection to really shoot for
the stars? It's after you've done your
very smart marketing, and you've got
your initial batch of users, and you
have KPIs that tell you your app is an
engine that works, that when it brings
users in through the front door, it
solves their problem and pushes revenue
out the other door.
Until you've proved that and you're
ready to put millions into your
marketing machine,
you don't need it. Forget it.
>> Or to your point earlier, if if you have
something you think you can build truly
defensible technology, then maybe
raising earlier does make sense. If
there's like a clear signal that if we
build this, it will make sense and we
can't build this without a certain
amount of money. Those would be the more
traditional kind of big doing early
stage funding.
>> many apps can you think of that needed
millions just to get going?
>> Callan AI is a great example. I actually
have, you know, my my respect for that
team has grown while I think for a lot
of people in this space their respect
for them has diminished as they released
the course and they've been doing all
these, you know, shirtless videos and
and stuff like that.
Uh you know, clearly you know, they're
young and everything, but if you look at
what they did, you know, they did start
super scrappy. And this is why early on
I really was very dismissive of them
because I opened the app and it was a
really crappy app. But they took that
crappy app that didn't actually work,
that didn't do what they said it was
doing. It I mean, honestly, and this is
again why I was like
dismissive of them early on. I was like
it doesn't do what they say it does. And
yet they're marketing it as this like
amazing solution. But to their credit,
they have since like actually built out
that tech. So So to your point, you
know,
maybe you build a painted door app
where you prove out that people are
willing to pay for this and then you go
build it. And that can work, but I think
there aren't a ton of categories that
you can do that in where that the app
that doesn't work will actually sell. I
mean, they were selling a lot of like
hopes and dreams and promises
>> Yeah, but they kind of um they doubled
down on something we said, you know, 10
minutes ago, which is distribution owns
the game right now. And these guys, you
know, Alex, Blake, Zach, they're killer
distributors. I've got like a kind of
bone to pick here because what they've
done is insane. Yeah, but every time
they jump on a podcast or an interview,
they talk to someone who's from like the
kind of success sphere or a kind of
growth marketer. I would love to get
like Alex and Zach like onto an app
podcast like this so we can push them on
things like paywalls, AB testing,
product depth, mechanics, etc. In fact,
let's call them out right now. I think
we should do that. So, Zach and Alex,
you've both got my phone number because
we've spoken in the past. I challenge
you to come here and jump on the podcast
with me and David. We're going to push
you on your actual app mechanics and
performance. Flights are on me between
Blue Throne and Revenue Cat, we can
probably cover it. I'd love to have you
here, and let's actually put you through
your app knowledge and see what's going
on there.
>> I'd love it, and and Blake, too. Blake
Blake is super smart.
>> yeah.
>> But anyways, what I was what I was
getting at with that is that I think
there are cases where where you're not
going to be able to do those kind of
painted door tests where you really have
to actually build the product first. I I
think that's more rare, but I think
there there are plays where that might
still make sense in 2025. I don't think
for every possible use case, for every
possible I mean I mean this is what's so
cool about this space though is that
like we're building things on these
little supercomputers in people's
pockets that can do such incredible
things. And and I feel like just over
the last like 5 years, the broader
industry is starting to wake up to just
how much opportunity there's still is in
mobile, and then
the subscription monetization
unlocking that long-term revenue and
being able to pay that back where I do
think starting today category leading
apps that are going to be billion-dollar
companies in the future can be built
today. Some of them may be built like
KAI where you you build an app that
doesn't work and hype it up really good
and you're incredible at distribution,
and then you figure it out. And again,
what I was where I was getting at
earlier is like KAI Ai a fantastic app
now and and and props to those guys.
It's genuinely a a great app. I watched
Blake on on a YouTube video with one of
the success guys. He actually drops a
lot of knowledge bombs in there in
between the like discussions of cocaine
and all sorts of other stuff about what
they're selling and one of the more I
thought cogent things he described is
that, you know, for people who are
tracking calories, it's not all about
being perfect in the calories. Even if
you have even if you log every food
perfectly and everything else like that,
it it you know, calories can vary,
people's metabolisms vary and all those
kind of things. And so one of the things
he said is like
by helping people just be more aware of
their food intake, by taking pictures,
by like just the act of tracking,
whether it's accurate or not, he claims
they're at like 90% accuracy with the
camera. I still doubt that.
>> know about that.
>> But he's right in that just the act of
tracking your food is going to help a
ton of people lose weight, get
healthier, you know, be more aware of
what they're putting in their body. And
so I I I think that's fantastic. And
hey, and and props to them. They're
selling it for 30 bucks a year, you
know, they're not charging $300 a year,
they're not charging 50 bucks a month or
something like that. The value that
they're delivering compared to what
they're charging, I think these days
it's actually incredibly favorable. Like
30 bucks a year for that app, I think is
a great value and I wouldn't be
surprised to see them have better
retention than a MyFitnessPal or some of
these other big apps that are charging
way more money because it's like, ah, 30
bucks, $29.99, like it's not that much
money. To circle this all the way back
around, um,
you know, I think there's opportunities
to do it that way, but then I also think
there's opportunities to build future
category leading billion-dollar apps
that will require much more investment
and I don't think as an industry we
should close our mind to that potential
just because an app like Calorie Ai
worked out the way it did. That's not
going to be
the norm and I don't think it's the only
way to do things. And so I do think that
there are apps that will require
investment to become the category
leader.
>> I think as we step strongly into this
marketing and distribution first
playbook for apps,
we're going to see the CEO founder be a
marketing guy.
And then we're going to see them hire or
outsource their dev work cuz it's not
that effective. I just wanted to
>> But but again, I think true for some
segment of the market, for some segment
of use cases, but I think we're going to
see technology forward CTO, ridiculously
talented programmer, amazing
technologist first
person who's going to build a category
leading company as well. I think we're
seeing this this like rise in that style
and the app mafia is a great example of
it, but I think that's one part of the
market. And I think they themselves are
maybe a little um
over indexing on that being the playbook
and the only thing that's going to work
moving forward or you're like the way to
build. I think that's one way to build.
I think that's one way that things are
going to be done. So yes, I think we
will see more of the kind of marketing
led CEO, non-technical led companies
that are built that way. And maybe you
know, maybe historically that's only
been 20% of the market and now it's
going to be 30, but I don't think this
is going to like take over the whole
market. I think it's going to continue
to be a spectrum.
>> Yeah, definitely a spectrum and we see a
lot of these technical first founders
who were great coders, but then can
apply the skill set of learning coding
to all the different bits and bites,
whether it's optimizing UA or building
out the infrastructure, optimizing that
team. And what you just said really
reminds me of um
a company we just bought in Brazil. It's
like some incredible technical founder
who is one of those jack-of-all-trades
that kind of learned through necessity
how to do a bit of everything, how to do
UA, how to build back end, front end,
etc.
And it just goes to show that if you can
kind of go on to that skill set and
build something that people want,
he uh you know, he lives in Brazil and
he walked away with like over $4 million
cuz he didn't raise any VC money. He
just built from the ground up from his
bedroom and within a year and I think 6
months of launching his app, he walked
away with like $4 million and the deal
went through in like 3 months cuz there
was no VCs to mess around with. It was
like straight to his bank account.
Crazy. And there are a lot of people
like that. We see them We see them all
around.
>> So, let's circle all the way back
We we chased a bunch of rabbits, but we
were talking about red flags for early
acquisition. I wanted to throw one more
in there.
And if you're building that kind of app
and you're thinking about an
acquisition, a huge red flag is to try
and juice numbers leading into an
acquisition. So, tell me about how what
you've seen and how bad that can be.
>> We've seen this a couple times where,
you know, founders are getting prepared
to sell.
And so, what they'll do is they'll try
and pump revenue to make that that
numbers look really good. And what does
that actually look like? What does that
mean? What does that mean? Pump revenue
or pump growth? So, so to pump revenue
would be something like in your your
paywall, you optimize the UI and UX so
that you're really pushing that lifetime
subscription, which is let's say $100,
right? Yeah. And your your monthly is 50
and your weekly is 10. So, suddenly
you're you're collecting those $100
much, much faster and more in the early
days, which on your P&L is going to
really bump up your revenue and
consequently bump up your profit or
EBITDA as well.
However, to the person who's about to
acquire that app, they suddenly cannot
monetize those users that you've just
sold a lifetime subscription to. So,
you're actually kind of shooting
yourself in the foot. We've seen it
happen a couple of times. I understand
why people do it. It just ends up like
um you know, knocking down the
negotiations further along the line,
which is not great. You can also pump
growth, right? You can also really put
your foot on the gas on marketing. We
see that happen as well. That's not as
bad because it actually collects a lot
of data for the acquirer and the seller
as to how effective marketing is when
you really try and push the buzz budgets
as high as you can go. And in fact, one
One the first questions I'll ask when
I'm getting to know a founder for the
first time is I'll ask what's your
marketing budget and they'll tell me I
don't know, 50k a month. And then my
second follow-up question is always how
high have you been able to push that?
And if you're not pushing it, why aren't
you pushing it? So, knowing the answer
to that is very important. There's a
flip side to this where the founder can
also optimize for profit. So, let's say
they're running at spending $50,000 on
marketing month over month, they think
about selling. So, they're like, "Hey, I
want to sell a profitable app cuz I'll
get a better multiple."
They cut marketing from 50 to 10.
And once they cut marketing from 50 to
10, they still kind of run off of the
cohorts they previously bought. But at
some point the downloads are going to
follow that drop as well. So, it can be
a problem as well. So, I'd say it's
if I was to categorize for anyone
listening like what's more dangerous,
optimizing for profit or revenue,
I'd always say it's more dangerous to
optimize for profit cuz you don't want
to mess with your download stream. It's
better to optimize for revenue.
>> Yeah. And to to that point, you know, if
you're spending a million dollars a
month and and on this podcast we've
we've talked a lot about paid
acquisition and not getting over
dependent on it and maybe like ideally
you're not, you know, spending every
penny on marketing. But even if you
don't have amazing retention, but you do
have a decent product and let's say
you're doing, you know, 40% annual
retention, which would be above me or
even if you're doing median like or
below slightly below median at like 30%
retention on your annual plans, if
you're spending a million dollars a
month this year,
that's 300k a month of free cash flow
next year if you can do that million a
month this year profitably or even break
even. So, if you're breaking even on a
million dollars a month of marketing
today and expanding and growing faster.
And so, this is to your point like if
you're optimizing toward revenue and you
have decent retention, an acquirer is
going to see that and see, "Okay,
so what? They're spending a million
dollars a month break even." As a you
just even as just a financial
instrument,
if you know that that retention is going
to be 30% ish, if you can predict that,
300,000 a month in free cash flow next
year, that's an attractive thing. And to
your point also is that you you at least
see that that's possible to spend at
that level and be at least break even if
not profitable on that spend.
>> I really agree with all your points and
I think we should like take two steps
back and put everything in a box for
people.
Different acquirers look for different
things. And we can pretty much split
them into three different acquirers. You
have your strategics, which are people
within your niche or within the larger
tech sphere that want your product for
maybe its features or its user base.
Let's give an example, right? If you're
building a dating app, a strategic buyer
would be Tinder, Bumble, Match.com, etc.
>> A great example of strategic buyer just
recently was Strava buying Runkeeper.
>> Exactly. That's a great example, right?
They're buying it for the users, for the
data, for the cross-selling. That's one
example. And by the way, founders, if
you're listening, like you can often get
a bigger multiple if you sell to
strategics.
>> And the team. Runkeeper was an
incredible team. And I know a lot of
those folks.
>> It can often be a great outcome. The
only downside to those outcomes is
they'll they'll look for a pretty big
earnout because they they spot you as a
talent and they want to keep you
internally. So, that's one. Second type
of buyer is more of a private equity
focused buyer who are basically looking
for profits or EBITDA. They want to see
really really great margins. These guys,
the upside is there's a lot of round.
The downside is they're going to want
you to stay on board because they don't
have the team to manage your app. They
need you to manage your app. And the
other downside is they're going to
optimize for like EBITDA, so it might
get a little bit messy. Not naming any
names, but they generally like to cut
the team.
Um then your third piece of the puzzle
is these kind of like app acquirers
similar to Blue Thorns and a bunch of
other in the industry. I'm not going to
do them any favors and shout them out.
Sorry, guys. But essentially, people
like us, we want to buy the app for its
future growth potential. And the
benefits there is that the founder
doesn't need to stay on for a super long
period of time. It's often a very, very
short handover with a lot of cash up
front. You kind of take the money and
walk away.
And companies like this will try and
take that app to be a category leader
and hold it there for as long as
possible. The first deal we did was in
was in the music entertainment space. It
was a solo founder. Uh we paid him
basically seven figures. Seven-figure
deal for an app he spent two years
building and the deal was closed within
two months. That was almost four years
ago. We bought it at about 200k MAU.
And since then, we added to the team. We
hired a killer GM from Spotify actually
to manage this music app. We grew the
team from five to 15 people and we grew
the MAU from 200k to almost 6 million
today and it's still pretty much top of
the category. When I'm talking to a
founder and they ask for a case study, I
always give that one. But actually,
because we're judged on our track
record, we have to be very strict about
the deals we do because one bad deal can
kind of torpedo the whole company. So
actually, our track record is great for
now. But with M&A and this kind of
playbook, you know, one bad deal can
really mess things up for good.
>> So in that third category that you were
just mentioning that you lumped Blue
Throne into, there is a very wide
spectrum. And so I'd say there is the
Blue Throne 1.0 of buying a ton of apps,
looking at more financial instrument. So
tell me about Blue Throne 2.0 though.
>> So Blue Throne 2.0, it's a great
question. Essentially, we learned our
lesson that buying this kind of wide
diverse portfolio of apps doesn't really
work cuz you're buying financial
instruments.
And at the end of the day, we were apps
guys and we knew apps and our team was
made up of guys from mobile gaming like
myself, from ad tech, and from consumer
tech.
So Blue Throne 2.0 is really about
finding apps that have found product
market fit, that have a lot of organic
traffic, which is a great signal for us
cuz it means no one is being paid to
download your app. They found it out of
word of mouth or K factor or just
searching for something on the App Store
themselves.
And these product market fit apps have
enabled themselves to rise to mid or top
of their category by providing a deep
product experience that solves the issue
they set out to solve.
That's the first thing. And we realized
if we acquired these and actually
invested in them and the team, we could
keep them as category leaders for as
long as possible and really turn them
into like standalone companies. And so
all the apps we buy have like a
significant brand image, they have
really strong organic traffic, they have
great retention, great resubscriber
rates, and of course like a killer
founding team. Now, sometimes the
founding team wants to stay and that's
great, we love that. We've had people
stay with us for like 3 years. Sometimes
they want to take their money, buy a
house, buy a car, pay off their parents'
house, and go. That's also fine with us.
The whole deal structure is about
finding what works for both parties.
But that strategy we've been employing
for
about 2 and 1/2 years now, and it means
our our portfolio is much smaller. We
now have a portfolio of five apps.
I saw your face there. Looks a bit
surprised there. It's true, it's only
five apps, but each app is either a
product leader in its category or on its
way to be. So it's a completely
different strategy, but luckily it's
working well for us now.
>> I've talked to the founders of Blue
Thorne a few times over the years, and
so I knew Blue Thorne as the old
strategy where there was like 100 plus
apps in the portfolio. And so when you
told me that Friday and then when you
told me it again today, it is surprising
because it's not what I remember and
think of Blue Thorne as. But it's
obviously a whole different ball game,
and and I I mean personally, you know,
if I were in the app acquisition space,
this is the approach I would be more
taking.
>> Which Blue Thorne 2 or Blue Thorne 1?
>> Blue Thorne Blue Thorne 2, yeah,
obviously.
>> you a question. If you could buy any
app, what would you buy as David?
>> Oh, that is a really good question.
Um
off the top of my head, I'd say my
friend Ryan Jens's app Flighty cuz it's
it's just one of those kind of category
leaders with so many opportunities. I
don't know that 50 million would do it
at this point. He's crushing it.
Um but you know, high retention,
you know, high willingness to pay, um a
lot of like ancillary uh opportunities
in the travel space to partner with
companies. So, like there's obvious like
future B2B plays. He's done almost no
paid acquisitions. It's very organic
growth.
>> I think my dream app is probably Opal,
the screen time app, for a few reasons.
One is
>> Well, they raised VC, though.
>> They did raise VC, so I'll be paying a
pretty penny for it. I don't know if I
can afford it, but I love this app
because the design is incredible. It
looks like it was built by Apple in
Cupertino itself. The problem it's
solving is super significant, basically
helping people stay off their phones.
And they've unlocked this crazy LTV. You
know what they charge yearly?
>> Mhm.
>> 120. 120 bucks per yearly. And the whole
logic, I've listened to a bunch of
interviews by by Kenneth, the founder,
who's super smart. The whole logic is
they target knowledge workers, and they
say, "If I can reduce your screen time
by 50% a week, you'll be making more
money in your in your probably
high-paying job." And that more money
you're making is well worth more than
the 120 bucks a year you're going to be
spending on my app. So, you're better
off spending the money. And it works.
It's a fantastic business that solves a
real problem. So, Kenneth, if you're
interested, come find me, but I'm I'm
also not sure I can afford you, but
yeah, shout out.
>> Well, I I love Opal, as well. I've had
Kenneth on the podcast. Actually, he
just emailed me this morning about our
App Growth Annual Conference. So, this
is not to take away from Opal, but let's
let's play it out. Some of the red
flags, some of the challenges in the
category. Because Opal and other apps
have done well, there's now a
proliferation of this these apps, and so
there's a ton of competition in the
space.
How have you been thinking about a space
like
screen time management? I assume I'm
going to put words in your mouth here,
but I assume it's that that even in
these spaces, there will be the kind of
category winner. So, that even if there
are 100 apps doing similar things, if
you can buy the category leader,
they're going to continue to thrive
regardless of what the competition is.
But you wouldn't want, based on Blue
Throne 2.0's positioning, you wouldn't
want to buy one of the 100 other apps to
go compete with Opal.
And you've probably looked at some of
them
because they're so clearly breaking away
from the crowd as the category leader.
Is that Is that how you think about
this?
>> So, you're you're a bit unlucky here cuz
I actually did analysis on this the
other week. So, I'm going to hit you
with some data here. Screen Time is a
really great category because if you do
a if you go on Sensor Tower and you do a
cross-section of downloads over time and
you stack them, there's a great viewing
way of doing this on Sensor Tower.
You can see that not only not only is
the category growing over time, which is
great ever since Apple allowed you to
use the API to to build these apps.
But, what you can see is that if you
cross-section it by downloads, every
time a new app enters the market, the
whole market grows. And to me as like a
an investor or a buyer, this tells me
there are users that the market leader
has not tapped into yet. That if a new
entrance comes in and has a different
value proposition or branding or appeal,
they can actually capture the capture
those users.
Um so, that's really interesting. And
the same thing happens with the revenue.
If you cross-section this category by
revenue, you'll also see that every time
a new company pops in and there's been,
you know, one from YC and a couple of
others, they're able to capture market
share without taking it from Opal even
though Opal is clearly the category
leader. So, in this
niche in particular, I would feel okay
with buying something that isn't a
category leader cuz I think there's
space for it to grow. You've also got to
remember that Screen Time is like a
pretty new category.
>> Yeah.
>> Weather apps, QR code scanners, they've
been around for decades.
Screen Time has only been around for
like less than 10 years, probably more
like six since Apple got the API.
Which brings me on to another topic of
like Sherlocking. You know, some might
say, "Well, hey, Apple is providing the
service organically on the phones
anyway, so why would you pay $120?" And
to that, I'd say, "Hey, if you offer a
better experience with an improved UI
UX, maybe some social features, you've
actually got space to grow in it and
that's been proven already."
>> And I I was laughing. The camera would
probably be focused on you during that
answer, but I was sitting across from
you laughing because as a parent, I can
tell you that their screen time
functionality sucks. And I I actually
was just uh talking on Twitter with
Kenneth, the founder of Opal. He said
this publicly on Twitter that they're,
you know, moving that direction and
wanted to like do a user interview with
me of like all the problems I have
managing my family screen time with
Apple's stuff. And And that's the thing
about Sherlocking is like Apple
does create great products generally,
but any one of their products is going
to have so many holes in it. And then
specifically, some of their products
just aren't great. And I would I would
lump
their screen time product into that.
There is a challenge there that as they
make it better, and this is an
interesting one, you know, I have a
weather app. And historically, Apple's
weather app has been crap. Well, they
actually did invest quite a bit. They
bought Dark Sky. They invested a lot in
the user experience and created a much
better default experience weather app.
Now, did that Did that take away from
the rest of the weather app market? I
actually don't think it did. Like I I
probably should sit down and do a much
deeper analysis like you've done. But
there is always the potential that they
will improve the product over time and
and it could cut into the opportunity
for that market to continue to grow the
way it has. But historically, that just
has not been the case. Fitness, they
came out with Fitness Plus and it's
bundled into the Apple One subscription.
And yet we see Run uh and Ladder and so
many fitness apps like Zero to One since
Apple launched Fitness Plus doing
incredibly well. So yeah, I don't think
Sherlocking and Apple providing it at
the system level or even as a add-on
like Fitness Plus should dissuade you
from playing in the category. In fact,
maybe that's a sign that it's a good
category to play in. And you go create
that better user experience and serve
the different use cases that Apple's
never going to serve.
>> Absolutely. Apple, for them it's a
question of focus and ROI and if they
the behemoth that they are turn their
attention something that you're looking
at, you're probably on the right track.
>> Yeah, totally.
All right. Well, I did want to dive into
another topic and we we've done so many
tangents we're we're not even going to
cover probably half the topics we were
planning on covering today.
Um but I did want to talk about
increasing LTV and kind of breaking
through some of the ceilings. It's
something I've been talking a ton about
hybrid monetization. We've seen early
leaders in the subscription space like
Tinder, you know, find ways to better
monetize through multi-tier
subscriptions, through consumables,
through one-time purchases. How do you
think about the opportunities ahead
because I think we're super early and I
love that you come from gaming because I
feel like gaming's perpetually 5 or 10
years ahead of the rest of the software
makers. So, how do you think about
hybrid monetization and and ways to
increase LTV not just by increasing
subscription
>> price.
>> Consumer apps on a subscription basis
typically have maybe four price points,
which is your your weekly, your monthly,
your yearly and your lifetime. And if
you imagine a graph with your X and Y
axis and a kind of
steps or stairs going up to the middle,
you're able to capture user willingness
to spend at four different points, the
price point of your weekly, monthly,
annual and lifetime.
>> Yeah.
>> Now, let me put a question to you app
founders out there. Let's say you're
charging
10 bucks for your monthly and you're
charging 100 for your yearly, but you've
got a user that's actually willing to
spend 75.
How do you capture that value? He's not
going to pay 100, he might pay 10, but
because he was willing to spend 75,
you're missing $65 worth of value.
Now, gaming cracked this a long time ago
because gaming works on this curve that
shoots up to the right and to the top of
the graph because gaming
uses gacha mechanics and in-app
purchases, one-time purchases for
example. So,
if a gacha box costs you 99 cents and
you're willing to spend $10, you'll make
that purchase 10 times and the app has
been able to capture all of the money
you were willing to spend.
So, how can you capture this from
consumer subscription apps? Well, the
solution we came to on Friday, which is
of no surprise to anyone, I'm sure, is
introducing in-app purchases, you know,
one-time purchases into your app. And
let's give an example. There's an
amazing app called SoundMap, for
example. SoundMap,
I spoke to the founder a while back now,
great guy called Zibo. SoundMap is
Pokémon Go for music. So, you walk
around your city using your phone and
you'll find tracks in your city and
you'll collect that music track, whether
it's like a Drake song, and then you'll
be able to trade that with someone else.
Maybe they've got a Metallica song and
you can trade that. So, there's
peer-to-peer sharing there as well. Now,
they have they have a subscription,
which is capturing the majority of the
value of the users, but they also have
consumables and power-ups that, for
example, let you discover two times more
songs in your area. So, they're able to
capture all the value of the users
they're willing to spend. And I think
the issue here for a lot of consumer
apps is that they don't all lend
themselves to this kind of monetization,
but the real unlock we've seen from Blue
Thrones level, talking to, you know,
hundreds of app founders a month, is the
ones that can crack this generally can
create deeper LTVs, which gives you way
more breathing room on your CPIs and and
your marketing budget.
>> Yeah, I think this is such an
underexplored space so far in the
non-gaming app world.
And,
you know, consumable IAP in some ways
are is probably the holy grail and this
is what we see with Tinder. And Tinder's
a perfect example. One of the things we
talked about over lunch was this famous
graph from Ravi Mehta, famous to me. I I
I just think
>> Not everyone is as deep into this as you
are.
>> But, it's looking at that willingness to
number of users across the horizontal
axis and then in the vertical axis, that
willingness to pay and and amount spend.
And what's so beautiful about Tinder's
model is that they have subscription
tier, a lower subscription tier that can
capture way more users at that lower
price, and they have a mid-tier
subscription where it's a higher price
but fewer users. And then they have the
highest paid subscription tier, which is
going to be the highest LTV subscription
with the lowest number of users. But
then, layered on top of those boxes is
those consumables where you can just
perfectly match that demand curve all
the way up and down. And so that is
optimal. But to your point, like not
every app can find that mechanic. I
would I would say, look for it. Like,
figure out if there's a way to do that.
But if you don't, there's a ton of other
hybrid monetization opportunities out
there. And one that I think is still
underexplored in subscription apps is
ads. And even rewarded ads is something
I've hardly seen in subscription apps,
but it's one of those things where, you
know, maybe if you're a scanner app and
somebody's got zero willingness to pay,
but they just need that one scan, maybe
you do a rewarded ad and or you're doing
an in-app purchase, you know, three
bucks just for the one scan and then
they can move on with their life. Now,
for most apps, and scanners are probably
a good example of this, you probably are
going to be a higher LTV,
you know, charging them on a weekly
subscription and certain amount of
people forget or whatever. But if you
can make those kinds of things work,
these are the unlocks we're going to
see. And then,
uh I'll be interviewing Michael Ribeiro
from Condé Nast at App Growth Annual
next month.
And this is something they're doing is,
you know, bundling subscriptions across
their products. After somebody
subscribes, offering physical goods.
Like there's there's so many ways to
build up those LTVs, not just with
consumables, not just with ads, not just
with rewarded ads, not just with Like
there's there's just so many ways to to
make that work. And then, you you know,
to our earlier conversation about Strava
and Runtastic, it seems like what
they're doing When Strava initially
acquired Runtastic, I was like, "Oh, it
makes so much sense. Like, they're going
to They bought a really amazing team.
They're going to like incorporate all
these amazing Runtastic features into
Strava. Oh, yeah.
Brilliant." And then, you know, 3 6
months later, you start seeing them do
subscriptions that get access to both
products. I was like, "Wait a minute.
They're looking at this as a as a
portfolio play, where they have
Runtastic standing on its own and bundle
in Strava, and maybe I I actually hadn't
looked specifically whether they're
doing that at a higher price point or
just using it to acquire more
subscribers because you're giving more
value by giving them both. But, I think
there's there's just so many creative
ways that we're going to be that this
industry is going to grow over time by
layering on different forms of
monetization.
>> Yeah, and let's try and um distill that
down into like one action item for like
the app founders listening. I always try
and do that cuz otherwise, there's so
much data coming out there.
The one action item is what's the
easiest lowest hanging fruit in order to
use either rewarded ads or one-time
purchases in your app. The answer is
just to build an an economy, to
introduce a soft currency, which is
gaming slang for
a way of um
building an economy that's not based
around dollars. So, it could be gems or
flowers or whatever whatever else it
might be. Once you have the economy, you
can then say, "Hey, here's a rewarded
ad, which if you watch, you'll earn 10
coins. Or, here's a option to buy five
coins, 10 coins, 15 coins at different
price points. And if you're not sure how
to do this cuz it's unfamiliar to you,
my best piece of advice would be A,
go and deconstruct the best mobile
games, Raid: Shadow Legends, the game I
used to work with, or Candy Crush, or,
you know, uh Match Royale, or any of the
Supercell games. Figure out how they're
doing it. And if you're still in the
dark, there are plenty of great
consultants who can help you build like
a gaming economy into your app.
>> Or, look at look at Tinder. and you
know, we had a podcast with the former
Tinder employee where he went in depth
about uh how they thought about layering
on those consumables. Uh so that's
another good example and and there's
there's a growing number of apps that
would be great examples to look at in
this space. And another thing I would I
would challenge folks on is there has
been a big move to hard paywalls and
that can be a very effective way to
monetize and to to get that return on ad
spend. But if you're trying to grow a
category-leading company and the TAM is
huge, most apps that do that are
probably going to need to have some kind
of free tier. And Duolingo's a great
example of this. Like they they would
never have become the company they
became. And I mean, you can even look at
the difference between Duolingo's and
Babbel. You know, Babbel has been a hard
paywall and Duolingo surpassed them even
though Babbel was older because they
allowed people to come in. And then what
do you see Duolingo doing now? They're
they've layered on consumables,
working harder at monetizing those
users. They have ads now. A lot of their
ads currently are for the subscription,
but you could see them layering on nice
branded ads. So Duolingo's actually
another good example for founders to
look at of like how they've managed to
do that with streak freezes and things
like that. Now, some of Duolingo's
mechanics are probably overplayed and
probably not going to work for your app.
I've had podcasts where we talk about
that as well. It's exciting to me
because I think there's just so many
opportunities and I think we're going to
see so much creativity. And then I'm
going to have fun on the podcast
dissecting what all these different
companies do over time to to make things
work. And like Ladder's a fun example.
They recently started doing physical
goods and I think for them right now,
it's just kind of like a little side
thing and it's not like a revenue
driver, but I could see that kind of
thing for a fitness app selling, you
know, doing an affiliate deal with Vuori
or or, you know, one of these big
fitness brands where they're selling
those clothes inside the app. People who
are into fitness are going to be buying
those things anyway. Can you create an
experience in the app where it makes it
better and then you do a rev share with
the brand or create your own brand of of
clothing that's as good or better than
these other brands and doing that inside
your app. I think there's just so many,
you know, I I was talking to the to the
founder recently about, you know, at
what point are you going to sell like a
home gym bundle? You know, where you
just go into Ladder and you're like,
okay, I want to join this team and the
team's great, but like, ah, it's hard to
find a bench at the gym and whatever.
Like, can you sell them a $3,000 like
home gym in a box, right?
>> LTV.
>> Yeah, I mean, that that's a thing. It's
like, you know, uh Ladder already has an
incredible LTV at $130 a year, but I
think there's so many opportunities when
you're a category leader, which I think
Ladder already is and is going to be
even more so recognized as a category
leader in the coming months and years,
they have a high willingness to pay in a
category that, you know, people are
willing to spend thousands, even tens of
thousands of dollars now as people are
looking at longevity and optimizing
their health. Like, it's a whole like
and then this is another like back to
your point earlier, like, are you
latching onto a trend that's growing or
that's like tapping out? And that's one
where they're latching onto a trend that
already been growing tremendously and I
think has room to continue growing time.
And so then there then there's just so
many opportunities for them and other
apps like that to diversify monetization
across all different kinds of things,
not just like kind of layer on this, you
know, one-time purchase. Like, for
Ladder, I think that might be a mistake.
That might not be a great answer for
them to try and like build mechanics
around that and maybe alienate some of
their hardcore users, whereas they have
so many other opportunities. And so I I
think it'd going to fun to see how the
industry progresses in the coming months
and years.
>> For sure. And a couple things to throw
on top of that. The first one is a piece
of advice for founders, which is how to
avoid a quite a significant risk. So, if
you do implement a hard paywall, and
Apple finds out about this, there's the
risk that they'll move your app from the
free category to the paid, which will
really mess with your ASO.
If it's a super hard paywall, yeah,
yeah, if they if they figure it out. So,
just like a word of warning there on
that one. Another thing to add is so,
when I was working at Plarium, the guys
who who made Raid: Shadow Legends, which
for those who don't know is is a huge
RPG kind of hero collection game that
was doing about a billion a year in
revenue at its peak. And one of my
projects back there was to build the
physical merchandise line for this game.
And so, we looked into the different
types of customers and what they were
willing to spend on and what their likes
were. And the way we were we were
analyzing it was
not as an additional revenue stream, but
how can I increase the LTV of these
users using physical products? And it
might be a mug for $6, it might be a
t-shirt for $20, or it might be like a
super premium hoodie for $50. And I know
that with my whales that are 2% of the
user base, give or take, that are
spending thousands of dollars on this
game,
I can then do this easy add-on of like a
premium product just to show off their
fandom for the game, and use that to
actually influence my marketing spend
cuz I'm actually increasing my LTVs
there.
>> That's really cool. I like that.
>> Yeah.
>> There's so much opportunity in this
space to figure out ways to to lever up
and grow in so many different ways.
>> For sure. And I wanted to pull the
conversation back to something else we
were talking about on Friday, which is
company strategy. We are seeing so many
companies and founders that are building
one app, and they'll kind of have some
luck with this, maybe after a few
failures.
And this question we were kind of
riffing on on Friday was like,
when does it make sense to go from a
single app company to a multi-app
company? And if you decide to go to a
multi-app company, should you buy or
should you build?
>> Right.
>> Um anything to chuck onto that?
>> Well, I mean, yeah.
We talked about this a lot on Friday.
Hard to summarize in a in a bite-size
podcast. So we're going to have to I'll
have to have you back on in the not too
distant future to cover the 20 other
things we could talk about. But I think
from my perspective and then I
definitely want to get you to tag on
here is that I do think a lot of
founders don't fully understand why they
were successful and maybe overestimate
their ability to pull off a second app
and run the playbook a second time.
I mean again we you know we're talking
about the Call AI guys, right? You know
their plan is to build a whole slew of
apps. Now,
you know, if you have lots of shots at
bat which they're in a position now
where they can take a lot more shots at
bat, I think
they're the kind of team and people who
will have successes, but they're also
going to have failures probably very
public failures along the way because of
how publicly they're doing all of this.
Um but if you expect to win every time
and you need a win to make it worth it,
you might be better off doubling down on
your existing app and and continuing to
grow that versus thinking you can run
that same playbook again and and make it
work again. I I think
the
you know the hindsight bias of like oh I
ran this playbook and it worked I can
run it again 10 more times.
Probably not.
Maybe like the unicorn
folks out there will. But what yeah what
are your thoughts on like and and you
know your you know another layer of this
is you know if you've had some success
you go buy another app and run your
playbook on the app that's already
showing some product market fit. And how
do you all think about it at Blue
Throne?
>> So let's break it down into two
questions. The first one is should you
go single app or multi app? And the
second question is if you go multi app,
should you buy or should you build? So
starting from the first question,
I would always tend to agree with you
which is stick with the thing that works
because at At end of the day the top
five apps are making 400x more revenue
than the bottom 25% of apps, and if
you've hit that product market fit,
it's a bit like a, you know, a flash in
the in the pan, so you want to kind of
hold on to it.
Now, building again from that and trying
to build a second app comes with very
similar risks to the first app, and
there's no guarantee you'll do it again.
So, which is why I don't I would
encourage a lot of founders out there to
actually start exploring buying apps.
And yes, this does add competition to my
industry, but that's fine. There's
enough to go around. And here, it's much
easier to measure
the ROI of your dollars spent. And one
of the frameworks we use at BlueThrone,
it is really the ROI of a dollar. So, if
I have a current app, and I know that if
I invest $1 into this app today, I'm
going to get back, you know, $50 by
month three, and then $200 by month 12,
whatever it might be, you have this
data.
When you're looking at buying another
app that you want to apply your playbook
to, you can say, "Hey, this app is going
to cost me a million, and the ROI I
expect is going to be X, because I know
their revenue is Y, and their
resubscribe rates are Z, etc., etc."
You're then in a position to directly
compare the ROI of that dollar to
whether you spent a million more dollars
on marketing your current app, because
you should know that data. So, as
founders, you're probably in a much more
powerful position than you realize to
actually go and analyze other apps in
the market, especially if you're looking
at apps within your niche, because you
can directly compare what's their
retention, what's their churn, what's
their price points, LTVs, etc. And you
can do a like-for-like comparison. And
there's so much supply in the market,
because AI is enabling developers to
build and execute and publish faster.
You'll probably be able to find stuff
that's kind of interesting to you.
>> Yeah, that's fascinating. I hadn't
thought about it from that perspective.
And this is one area I think a lot of
folks, especially who were early in the
App Store, like kind of my peers who
were building apps in like 2010, 2015,
and like today, they're, you know,
they're doing millions of dollars a year
in revenue,
whether it's SEO or something else.
Like, having some kind of organic
channel that's succeeding
often times is what helped to those apps
into the position that they are in
today.
So, you want to really deeply understand
that of like the success of your current
app, and then looking at potentially
buying another app, what you may be
buying is somebody who also cracked
that, and then you can layer on, you
know, the paid I mean, there's so many
apps that do get to 10, 20, you know,
30k a month in revenue. You could
probably buy them for not that much
money, but they haven't even you know,
done a paywall test. They haven't done
any paid marketing. And so, yeah, if
you're a founder and you're really good
at paid marketing and viral Tik Tok, or
you
you know how to work with influencers
and stuff like that, I I think that is a
really cool opportunity to like find
some of those apps who who have that
traction and then double down on them.
>> Absolutely. And there's supply, there's
opportunity out there to do it. More
people should.
>> We need to wrap up, but um
I know you you prepared a fun little
quiz for me
with some data you pulled over the
weekend. So, let's wrap it up with that,
cuz I think it'd be a lot of fun.
>> Sure. So, at Blue Thorne, we're talking
to like a over 100 founders a month.
Like it it's crazy at this point. We've
got quite a big team for it. So, I went
back into the CRM and I looked at the
last 100 founder meetings we've had over
the last 2 months, and I calculated some
stats. I'm going to throw you a
question, you tell me what you think,
all right? Of the last 100 founder
meetings, how many do you think were
building an AI note-taking app?
>> Yeah, I just saw somebody tweeting about
this.
I think it was don't go build a AI
note-taking app. So, I'm going to guess
it's high, maybe 30%?
>> Oof, it's it's not that high. It's it's
nine. So, it's closer to 10%, which
considering the number of categories out
there, it's still pretty pretty
competitive.
>> That's crazy, though.
>> Next question maybe reveals a bit of a
harrowing truth about our industry, but
how many do you think were female
founders?
>> Not many.
Um I do worry apps is turning into the
next drop shipping, and there's going to
be a lot of uh
Whatever it is is like drop shipping bro
is the caricature for a reason.
I'm going to say less than
10%.
>> Yeah, it's it's two. It's super super
and maybe that's a factor of like a
success bias thing as well, but it was
only two which I think we need to change
to be honest.
>> Yeah.
>> All right, of the last 100 founder
meetings, how many do you think
successfully raised VC funding for their
app?
>> Well, I know you're going after
bigger, more successful apps now. You're
not just kind of spray and pray with a
bunch, so probably had higher quality
100 founder meetings, but
I'm going to go low on this one and say
less than
40%.
>> Yeah, it was pretty low. It was it was
close to 20%.
>> Yeah.
>> Um but we are seeing more and more um
pop up these days.
>> It's a time in the industry where a lot
of apps were able to raise in 2021 when
money was free and so now's about the
time they've, you know, already cut the
team, they've run out of cash, they're
kind of looking for the kind of exit
that BlueThorn would provide versus like
a strategic buyer or an IPO or something
like that, so
>> And then they're now like raising their
heads, right? They're now kind of out in
the market, so we'll see them.
>> Yeah.
>> All right, last two for you. Of the last
100 founder meetings, how many were just
solo founders with no full-time team
around them?
>> Oh, I'm going to guess a ton on this
one. I'm going to go high, over 50%.
>> It wasn't that high, but it was it was
high compared to the other ones. It was
34% which is which is still quite a lot.
A third of founders that we're speaking
to are solo founders which is pretty
impressive, I think.
>> Well, especially impressive given the
criteria of who you talk to.
>> Yeah, yeah. No, it's definitely the time
to to build solo. And the last one I
think cuz we're in the US, I thought I'd
chuck a US one, but how many were
US-based founders of the last 100?
>> I'm going to go lower on this one, like
less than 30%.
>> No, actually it was a little bit higher.
It was 45%.
>> terrible.
>> Yeah.
I made it hard cuz it was out of 100.
So, if I did it out of 10, it would have
been easier. But, I think the US just
has all the tools you need to build
these really great products. And there's
a key reason there's a key reason here
which if you if someone on who's
listening is doing TikTok marketing,
they're going to know exactly what I'm
about to say, which is to smash it on
TikTok, you have to have your TikTok
account based in the US. So, naturally,
US founders always have an advantage,
really. So, these guys are actually
doing doing better compared to people
around the world who have to figure out
a kind of VPN and buy a SIM card, and it
gets very complicated.
>> that's the most surprising stat of this
whole conversation to me. Just because I
I I talk to so many founders all across
the world, and you know, so many great
founders coming out of Europe, Eastern
Europe, Asia, you know, India. I've been
surprised at how global the app industry
is even though the US is the primary app
market where users do spend most of
their money. I mean, this may be kind of
a bias in, you know, your travels and
stuff, but, you know, RevenueCat, we've
been looking at the data, and Japan and
South Korea are two of the largest
markets on in the world, and combined
are closing in on some of these larger
markets as well. Um so, you have US,
then China, then Japan and South Korea.
And I think those markets, language
barrier, culture barrier, everything
else, are a little
underrepresented in in the broader kind
of subscription app ecosystem. You know,
US events, you're not going to run into
a lot of them because language barrier,
you know, RevenueCat, we recently did a
thing in Japan, and um hired somebody in
South Korea. Thriving ecosystems in
those countries, but they are fairly
isolated. So, uh so, yeah, surprising to
me, but maybe a little maybe your stats
are a little biased. If we took the the
the kind of
>> It's definitely not like a global uh
representation of the population.
There's some sort of success bias here
as well.
>> Well, that was fun. So, thanks for
bringing the data and I think tossing it
back and forth is was insightful and
kind of interesting. So, thank you.
And uh but as we wrap up, uh you always
give a guest an opportunity to share,
you know, anything you want to share. If
you're hiring, looking for apps, or
anything else you kind of wanted to talk
about as we wrap up.
>> Sure. So, uh Blue Thum we're full steam
ahead on looking for our next basically
app to acquire and maintain its like
market leader position.
Uh our budgets range from two all the
way up to 50 million to basically
acquire the next big app. And if you're
building and have scaled already and
want to basically look for your exit and
get cash in the bank having built for
for many, many years,
um then feel free to reach out to me on
LinkedIn, Josh
Maybe we'll share my email in the show
notes as well. But, yeah.
Dude, thanks for having me.
>> What's the uh what's the minimum you
would say? Minimum annual revenue you
would consider?
>> Probably about 500k. Okay. That's the
minimum annual revenue we'd we'd kind of
go for just cuz there are like costs
involved in getting, you know, all those
processes started and the the the
acquisition has to be worth it.
Um but the core driver is really that
the performance of the app, right? The
KPIs internally and and the talent of
the founder behind it.
>> Yeah. Well, it's been a blast talking to
you. Well, we'll have to hang out at
AppGrowth Summit in a few weeks.
>> Dude, I can't wait. I'm going to be
coming back to New York just for your
event.
>> Yeah, and I'll have to have you back on
the podcast sometime. So, thank you so
much.
>> much, man.
>> Thanks so much for listening.
If you have a minute, please leave a
review in your favorite podcast player.
You can also stop by chat.subclub.com
to join our private community.